So before we leave this section I want
to show you the Kotlin read eval in
print loop, also known as the repl now
maybe they say that as a repl, I don't
know the repl lets you practice your
Kotlin and you can also use it to
quickly check whether a code snippet
will work. So in IntelliJ you can get to
it by going to tools Kotlin and then
down to Kotlin repl here and you'll
notice that it opens up at the bottom
and there's a great outline here saying
ctrl + enter to execute remember that,
because you'll tend to hit enter
and then wonder why nothing is happening.
So now we can type any expression into
the repl and we hit ctrl enter and it
will be evaluated for us, so let's try
3 + 4 and we hit ctrl enter and we'll see
that 7 comes up and you'll notice that
there's an equal sign here so this is
the result of the expression up here.
Let's try 5 minus 2 and the other way
that we can execute an expression is
just to click the green run-button here,
button rather and we'll see that we get 3,
Now, you'll notice that above the
repl window it says in module
declarations, the repl knows about the
definitions in your project so we can
reference them. So for example we could
start typing employee and it will
actually suggest the employee definition
that we have in our project. So let's go
back and type var employee 3 equals
employee give him the name John Doe and
let's give him an ID of let's say 300.
Now, we have to declare our employee here
and then we'll import it into the repl.
Also, it's underlined employee 3 just as
it does in the editor, because it's
mutable. Now we don't want to run yet
because there's no expression here, we're
just doing an assignment statement.
So we'll just go to then to the end of
the line press enter and then we'll say
well print line employee 3.
And at this point there is something we
can do, so we'll hit ctrl enter and we'll
see that we get employee 3 printed.
Now, because we're in the repl, we don't
actually have to use print line, so we
can just type in employee 3 dot name for
example and then hit ctrl enter and it
will print John Doe, so it kind of knows
that because you're in the repl, you
want to see results and so it doesn't
force you to actually type print line,
but you can if you want.
So the repple knows about definitions in
your project, you do have to import them
but it's aware of them and it also knows
about previous definitions you've made,
like for example once we declared
employee 3 here, we didn't have to
declare it again. Once we've used it we
can just go ahead and keep using it in
this instance of the of the repl, so if
you want to play with some code, without
having to compile and run it, this is a
great way to do it and you know when
you're first learning Kotlin, before you
type a long statement into your file, you
might want to try the repl and make
sure it's going to do what the
statements going to do, what you expect
it to do. Now when you're finished
playing, you can just press the red X on
the left to stop and close the repl,
if you don't want to close it, but you want
to clear what's there and rebuild your
project, you can just press the restart
button right here. So if we were to do
that, it actually rebuilds our project
here and then it comes and says ok, I'm
ready for action again or you can just
close it and I've got a couple of tabs
open here, so I'll close them all and
there we go, that's the Kotlin read eval
print loop. I'll see you in the next video.